Guide to the Wooden Teeth literary magazine, 1978-2015 MS2334.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Wooden Teeth literary magazine
1978-2015
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MS2334.UA
2 Linear Feet
Wooden Teeth is GW's premier visual arts and literary student publication, soliciting contributions from GW students, faculty, and staff of both written and visual works. Beginning life in the 1970's as the Rock Creek Review, Wooden Teeth is now published bi-annually at the end of each spring and fall semester. Material in this collection range in date from 1978-2015.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of Wooden Teeth, The George Washington University arts and literary magazine. The materials range in date from 1978-2015.
Biographical / Historical
Wooden Teeth is GW's premier visual arts and literary student publication, soliciting contributions from GW students, faculty, and staff of both written and visual works. Beginning life in the 1970's as the Rock Creek Review, Wooden Teeth is now published bi-annually at the end of each spring and fall semester. The editors court controversial and cutting-edge contributions, seeking to push boundaries in literature and the arts, while not lapsing into sensationalism. The editors are highly selective, often rejecting up to 90 percent of submissions in order to guarantee a high level of quality. Wooden Teeth also sponsors monthly on-campus performances and readings of poetry, short stories and songs in order to foster creative and critical thinking about the arts in the GW community.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Other Finding Aids
The predecessor to Wooden Teeth, Rock Creek Magazine has issues in RG0115 series 4. http://library.gwu.edu/ead/rg0115.xml Issues of Rock Creek Magazine in RG0115 range in date from 1971 to 1978.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Original donation was transferred 2014 November 20. Addition donation from Margaret Carleen, 2014 November 18 (2014.039).
Literature; Student publications; Poetry
- Volume 1:1, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Volume 1:2, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Volume 2:1, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Volume 3:1, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Volume 3:2, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Volume 4:1, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Volume 4:2, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Volume 5:1, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Volume 5:2, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Volume 6:1, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Volume 6:2, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Volume 7:1, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Volume 7:2, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Volume 8:1, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Volume 8:2, 1986
- Volume 9:1, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Volume 9:2, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Volume 10:1, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Volume 10:2, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Volume 11:1, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Volume 11:2, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Spring Volume 12:1 and12:2, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Fall Volume 13:1, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Spring Volume 13:2, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Fall Volume 14:1, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Fall Volume 15:1, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Spring Volume 15:2, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Fall Volume 16:1, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Spring Volume 16:2, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Fall Volume 17:1, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Spring Volume 17:2, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Fall Volume 18:1, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Spring Volume 18:2 and Fall 19:1, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Spring Volume 19:2, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Fall Volume 20:1, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Spring Volume 20:2 and Fall Volume 21:1, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Spring Volume 21:2, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Fall Volume 22:1, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Spring Volume 22:2, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Fall Volume 23:1, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Spring Volume 23:2, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Fall Volume 24:1, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Spring Volume 24:2, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Fall Volume 25:1, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Spring Volume 25:2, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Fall Volume 26:1, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Spring Volume 26:2, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Fall Volume 27:1, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Spring Volume 27:2, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Fall Volume 28:1, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Spring Volume 28:2 and Fall Volume 29:1, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Spring Volume 29:2 and Fall Volume 30:1, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Spring Volume 30:2 and Fall Volume 31:1, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Spring Volume 31:2 and Fall Volume 32:1, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Spring Volume 32:2 and Fall Volume 33:1, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Spring Volume 33:2 and Fall Volume 34:1, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Spring Volume 34:2 and Fall Volume 35.1, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Spring Volume 35:2 and Spring Volume 36:1, 2013-2014 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Spring 2015 Vol. 37, No. 1 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Baby Teeth, volume 3, issue 1, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Rock Creek, 1974-1978 (Box 5, Folder 1-5)